A Guide to the Near East Foundation records Accessions 2009.104, 2010.002, 2010.020 FA406
Rockefeller Archive Center
Near East Foundation records
1915-2003
1940-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Near East Foundation
FA406
192.8 Cubic Feet 161 standard record storage boxes, 1 1/2 letter size document boxes
The Near East Foundation records consist of approximately 173 storage boxes of archival material
Biographical / Historical
Cleveland H. Dodge and a group of New York philanthropists formed the Committee for Armenian and Syrian Relief in 1915 (as a response to American Ambassador to the Ottoman Empire Henry Morgenthau's plea for assistance). The Committee was chartered by the U.S. Congress as "Near East Relief" (NER) in 1919.
John D. Rockefeller Sr. was one of the first major contributors to the NER. During World War I, the NER is credited with saving 1 million lives of Armenians, Assyrians, Arabs and Persians. From 1915-1930, the NER raised $110 million for refugees. Among its accomplishments, the NER: fed 12 million people; built 40 hospitals; and housed, fed and educated 132,000 children in orphanages and provided them with medical care.
In 1930, Near East Relief officially changed its name to the Near East Foundation and refocused its activities, beyond refugee relief, to become the first international development organization with the objective of catalyzing long-term sustainability through vocational education, training and agricultural programs including experimental projects and instruction.
NEF identifies local communities in need of development assistance, and mobilizes them into grassroots civil society organizations that work to create homegrown solutions to the community's problems.
NEF staff is native members of the communities that they work in. They help guide the people of the community through stages of problem-solving, effective collaboration, and the formation of responsive civil society organizations to develop self-sustaining activities, programs and long-term societies. NEF commonly operates in active yet unstable settlements. These communities are generally beyond the emergency relief stage, yet they need systemic development assistance to build stability and facilitate their long-term survival. NEF operates in Albania, Bulgaria, Greece, Egypt, Lebanon, Mali, Morocco, Sudan, Syria, and throughout the Middle East and Africa.
The NEF's "self-help" approach created the models for the Marshall Plan, Truman's Point-4 Program, the Peace Corp, the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and the United Nations Development Program (UNDP).
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the Near East Foundation (1930-2003, bulk 1940s-1980s), focusing on its international development and technical assistance programs at the country and local community levels. Its focus on developing problem-solving civil society organizations, international relations, vocational training and sustainable international development, compliments many of the RAC collections, and tells an important philanthropic story of a region of the world not particularly well represented by other RAC holdings.
Materials include but are not limited to: project files, USAID task orders and reports, Administration files, donor files and donor cards, financial statements, personnel files and contracts, publications, and documentation of special events. There are extensive, rich, and historically significant files documenting NEF projects and activities throughout the Near East, Middle East and Africa.
The files, reports and task orders documenting the NEF work with the Agency for International Development (AID) are also extremely rich and highly significant for scholarly research purposes.
Documentation of the Near East Relief period (1915-1930), and those records related to the Armenian genocide, is limited and sporadic. (Select portions of the following boxes document this early period: 96, 97, 129, 133-139, 144, 145, 153, 155, 156, 161.)
The collection also contains a high volume of special format holdings including: photographs, slides, albums, scrapbooks, audio cassettes, film strips, and various items used in the 2003 exhibition at the Museum of the City of New York.
Arrangement
NEF records are intellectually arranged loosely into series to facilitate scholarly access. The collection remains physicallly arranged as received by Rockefeller Archive Center.
All users of this collection guide are encouraged to refer to the entire guide when considering materials that may be pertinent or otherwise relevant to their research.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Near East Foundation records were donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center by NEF in June 2011.
The initial short-term deposit of the NEF records was adopted in 2009, at which time all the NEF records onsite at RAC were comprehensively accessioned as 2009:104 (approx. 149 cu. ft). Additional materials have been sporadically received and accessioned accordingly.
RAC obtained physical custody of the NEF records on March 3, 2005. Much of the material transferred to RAC in 2005 arrived in the original metal filing cabinets, and was subsequently re-housed into archival storage boxes
Separated Materials
Various photographs and special formats have been separated from the body of the collection to address their specific storage and preservation needs.
- AC.2009.104: Near East Foundation records, 1915-2003; 1940-1980; AC 2009:104; 180 Cubic Feet 168 boxes, including 150 standard record storage boxes
  - Project Files
    - NEF/Africa - Cameroon - Misc., 1973-1978 (Box 7)
    - NEF/Africa - Cameroon - Project Proposal, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - Cameroon Poultry Extension Education, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
    - West Cameroon Poultry Report, 1965-1967 (Box 7)
    - Mauritius Young Farmers Clubs, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Mauritania Rural Development Survey - Dr. Downs - Wm. Isom - N. Martin, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Mali - Purchasing, shipping & supplies
    - Mail - Reports, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Togo - NEF/Africa Program, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Health Economist (ADB), 1979 (Box 7)
    - Africa - Ministry - Directors - Etc., 1975-1978 (Box 7)
    - NEF Fisheries Project - Botswana, 197-1979 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Memo of Working Agreement - Ministry Agri. & NEF, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Memo of Understanding - M.A.C.U. & NEF, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Misc. Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - End of Tour Report - N.C. Anderson, 1974 June 28 - 1976 June 27 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Nels Anderson - Report - Work Schedule, 1975 (Box 7)
    - Gary Bond - Report Marketing Branch - Botswana, 1975-1976 (Box 7)
    - ED COE End of Tour Botswana, 1978 March (Box 7)
    - Botswana - James Dunn - Report, 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Fisheries Project Report - Kirby S. Gilmore, 1975-1978 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Management Plan for Selebalo Group - Ranch - Western Ngwaketse by Paul Jenkins, 19876 (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Report by D. Light, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - D. Olson - Botswana - Feasibility Study Report - Kanase Farmers' Project Monthly Reports, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Report on the Feasibility of a Mechanical Brigade - Kasane 1976 by Robert H. Horning (no folder) (Box 7)
    - Botswana - Report by Chala Peavy, 1977 June 30 (Box 7)
    - Preliminary Range Utilization Studies - Botswana - Special reference to Western Ngwaketse Van Voorthizen, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Walker, G. - Cobb, R. - Withers, J. AID/Africa Ethopia, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - Pulse Project Annual Report - M.Marvel - Ethopia, 1976 (Box 8)
    - D.M. Dunbar - End of Tour Report, Kenya - E.A.C., 1976 (Box 8)
    - Kenya /Fisheries - Final Report - Muller, 1976 June - 1978 March (Box 8)
    - Nelson, Charles, A.I.D. (Kenya), 1975-1977 (Box 8)
    - End of Tour Report - Lesotho - Cooper, H.W. (no folder), 1975 September 1 - 1979 October 16 (Box 8)
    - End of Tour - Powell - Lesotho, 1978 December (Box 8)
    - Thaba Bosiu Rural Development Project - Lesotho, 1974-1979 (Box 8)
    - Lesotho - Quarterly Report - Hurelbrink, 1976 October-December (Box 8)
    - Lesotho - Final Report - J.B. Swecker, 1976 January - 1978 January (Box 8)
    - V.E.M. Burke - A.I.D. (Lesotho) - Harry Johnson, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Lesotho - R. Flannery - End of Tour, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Lesotho - Final Report - A.J. Andresen, 1975 October - 1977 October (Box 8)
    - Lesotho - Family Planning materials & report on: Lesotho Food & Nutrition Planning and Research (no folder), 1976 January (Box 8)
    - Flannery, R. D. - Publications, 1972-1978 (Box 8)
    - Malawi Informational Material, 1975-1980 (Box 8)
    - Malawi Government - Budget Reports 2,3,4, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Malawi Proposal, 1970-1976 (Box 8)
    - Swaziland - Report by L. Osburnsen, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
    - Frank Ferentcheck's Terminal Report - Swaziland, 1979 August (Box 8)
    - Swaziland, 1978 (Box 8)
    - AID/Africa Swaziland - Clark, Ralph - Johnson, Wm. - Ward, Chas., 1975-1977 (Box 8)
    - Highveld Ranch - Annual Report - Swaziland by Richard Aro, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Range Development & Management - F. Abercrombie, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Tanzania - Quarterly Report #1-5 by Alex Powers, 1975-1979 (Box 8)
    - Cornelius, Jack - A.I.D. (Tanzania), 1975-1977 (Box 8)
    - Masai Project - End of Tour Report and Special Report - C. Hatfield, 1975-1978 (Box 8A)
    - Tanzania - Progress Report Masai Project - J. Fisher, 1976 November - 1977 April (Box 8A)
    - Tanzania - Final Report - Masai Project - Dr. Jacobs, 1977 (Box 8A)
    - Tanzania/Fisheries - Final Report - Gary Kukowski, 1978 April (Box 8A)
    - Tanzania - Roads Project, 1977 April (Box 8A)
    - Tanzania-Masai Range Report by Don Moris, 1976 (Box 8A)
    - Tanazania - End of Tour - Masai Project Report by Dick Stanley, 1976 (Box 8A)
    - Masai Project End of Tour VANCE, 1977 September - 1979 September (Box 8A)
    - Tanzania - End of Tour Report - VORHIS, 1977 February 16 - 1979 April 30 (Box 8A)
    - NEF Investment Portfolio Summaries, 1980-1986 (Box 8A)
    - World's Sunday School Association, 1930-1935 (Box 9)
    - Sivitanides Foundation of Arts & Trades, Inc. - Athens, Greece, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Russian Contracts, 1925-1933 (Box 9)
    - Bulgarian Folk School & Rural Center - Dr. Haskill, Principal, 1931-1934 (Box 9)
    - Beirut Playground, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Athens Tubercular Pavilion, 1930-1932 (Box 9)
    - Athens Playground, 1930-1931 (Box 9)
    - Armenian Government Bonds, 1920-1943 (Box 9)
    - Antilyas Committee, 1933 (Box 8)
    - International College of Smyrna, 1931 (Box 9)
    - Emhardt Promissory Note, 1928-1933 (Box 9)
    - Stuart & Hollinshead Contract, 1932 (Box 9)
    - Rush Case, 1935 (Box 9)
    - Fothergill-Odell Loan, 1932 (Box 9)
    - Caucasus File Index, 1920-1931 (Box 9)
    - Seattle Property - Deeds & Mortgage, 1929-1939 (Box 9)
    - Promissory Note - Timothy P. Malouf, 1933-1939 (Box 9)
    - Chicago Exposition - Century of Progress, 1933 (Box 9)
      - Hall of Religion Blueprint, 2016:FA406:003 (Folder SF3)
    - Wertheim Contract, 1933 (Box 9)
    - Lemmon State Bank (Lemmon, S.D.) Certificate of Claim Against (Box 9)
    - Athanas Ouzounoff - Promissory Note, 1933 (Box 9)
    - Resignation of Mr. Vickrey, 1929 (Box 9)
    - Lilla Downer Release, 1926 (Box 9)
    - Mrs. Jacobson's Responsibility in Re Trust Funds for Diliminasian & Boshguzonian, 1935 (Box 9)
    - Bulgarian Contract - Re: Whipple, 1936 (Box 9)
    - Nurse Training: Salliari, Katy; Papazafiro, Marietta; Georgala, Penelope; Spinari, Myrto, 1937-1947 (Box 9)
    - Duryca, Alice, 1922-1923 (Box 9)
    - Sophia Papadopoulou - Blind Scholarship, 1937-1938 (Box 9)
    - Employees Benefit Fund (old records) Contract File 80-B, 1945-1969 (Box 9)
    - Iran Vermin F #119, 1955-1958 (Box 9A)
    - Weekly News Reports #1-42 "Where Are They Now?" #1 on NEF News Quarterly - April 1959, 1954-1955 (Box 9A)
    - Survey - Jordan Contract #117 (Box 9A)
    - Terminal Report of Community Development & Rural Dev. Advisory Services Republic of Korea, 1959-1963 (Box 9A)
    - AID Items, 1967-1977 (Box 9A)
    - AID Correspondence - All Contracts - Desk File, 1975 (Box 9A)
    - Mauritania Trial Balance (folder unlabeled), 1974 (Box 9A)
    - Budget (folder unlabeled), 1976 (Box 9A)
    - T/O Jobs Worksheets - All other countries, Cameroon, Iran, Jordan, Leban, 1975-1976 (Box 9A)
    - Budget (folder unlabeled), 1976 (Box 9A)
    - D/O Jobs Worksheets, 1975 (Box 9A)
    - AID - Task Order Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 9A)
    - expenses, etc. (folder unlabeled), 1973 (Box 9A)
    - Trial Balance - African Ledger T/O's, 1975 January 31 - December 31 (Box 9A)
    - Financial Info. (folder unlabeled), 1973-1975 (Box 9A)
    - Trial Balances Afr. 193, 1967-1972 (Box 9A)
    - Iranian Student "5", 1952-1954 (Box 9A)
    - Rural Credit Program (FORD), 1953-1962 (Box 9A)
    - #115 LEtter from Greek Government asking for program with FOA, 1951-1954 (Box 10)
    - Invitation from Iraqi Government - Letter H-256, 1953 (Box 10)
    - File #110: Iran - SCC-14559 - A/C 3 also referred to as "C", "D", "E", 1953-1958 (Box 10)
    - Bank Signatures #112, 1964-1979 (Box 10)
    - Ivory Coast - African Development Bank (ADB), 1977-1982 (Box 10)
    - Ivory Coast - ADB Recruitment, 1982-1986 (Box 10)
    - Ivory Coast - ADB Rejects, 1982-1986 (Box 10)
    - Ivory Coast - ADB Attachments, 1972-1984 (Box 10)
    - Kenya - International Conference on Apiculture (Floyd Moon), 1984 (Box 10)
    - Nigeria - Kano State Institute, 1980-1984 (Box 10)
    - Nigeria - Kano State Institute - Herbert Brownlee Reports, 1981-1983 (Box 10)
    - Swaziland: Angora Goat Project, 1979-1987 (Box 10)
    - Zambia - Fabian Zulu Project, 1984-1986 (Box 10)
    - MEAR: Seed Distribution Project, 1975-1986 (Box 10)
    - Middle East - Amideast - Nurse Training Project, 1984-1986 (Box 10)
    - MEAR: International University Foundation - Water Challenge Conference, 1984 (Box 10)
    - MEAR: Internatl. Univ. Fdn. Water - Challenge Conf. - Attachment: File #2, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Jordan Attachment File (Box 10)
    - MEAR: Internatl. Univ. Fdn. Water - Challenge Conf. - Attachment: File #1, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Jordan - Ministry of Social Development, 1981-1984 (Box 11)
    - Ministery of Social Development - Jordan - James Phillips - Youth Program Spec. Reports, 1981-1984 (Box 11)
    - Jordan - Mary Roche - Women's Program Spec. - Reports (MSD), 1981-1985 (Box 11)
    - Jordan - Stephen Roush - Rabbit Proj. - Rabbit Specialist - Reports, 1981-1985 (Box 11)
    - Jordan - Rabbit Production - Attachment Folder, 1977-1983 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - American University of Beirut (AUB), 1969-1987 (Box 11)
    - Report: A Problem Detection Study of Charities by BBDO Research, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - AUB - Melkon Markarian Scholarship Fund, 1981-1986 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - AUB - Dr. Lawrence C. Parker Reports, 1980-1983 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - AUB - Rice, Robert P. & Laura W. - Horticulturists Reports, 1983-1986 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - AUB - William Russell - Ext. & Research Agronomist - LL Corre., 1980-1983 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - AUB - Thomas Zimmerman - Agriculture Engineer Reports, 1981-1984 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - American University of Beirut, Attachment Folder II, 1982-1986 (Box 11)
    - Lebanon - American University of Beirut Attachment Folder I (Box 11)
      - The NEF at Work in Lebanon, 2009:104:001 (Box 11)
    - Afghanistan Reports - Mason Beers - Area Director, 1955 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan Reports - N. Mason Beers - Area Director, 1956-1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan Reports - Pictorial Reports, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan Reports - Louis E. Andrew - Agronomist, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Agriculture - "Farm implements and tools used by farmers in the Logar Valley", 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Allen, H.B., 1955 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 December (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 November (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 October (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 September (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 August (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 July (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 June (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 May (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 April (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 March (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 February (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1956 January (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 December (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 November (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 October (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 September (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 August (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 July (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 June (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 May (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Beers, 1955 April (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Cable confirmation, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Cables Outgoing, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Cars, 1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Cars, 1955-1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Contract Matters, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan to Lebanon, 1955 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan Plan of Work, 1955 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - 5 Year Plan for Rural Develop., 1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Flegel, 1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Government, 1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Hayden, 1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Hayden, 1955 August (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Hayden, 1955 May (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Hayden, 1954 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Helmand Valley region: Proposed Rural Development Program, 1955 November (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - "Helmand Valley: Management & Operations" New Contract Proposal, 1957-1959 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Helmand Valley Survey, 1958 (Box 28A)
    - "Housewife's Report on Afghanistan" by Jane Howard, 1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Howard, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Howard, 1956 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Kanalz, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan Article - Life Magazine, 1956 April 9 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Maps, 1955 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Office - Purchasing, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - "Packing for Novices and What to Take to Afghanistan" by Mrs. Price (Box 28A)
    - Afghanistan - Program and Policy, 1957 (Box 28A)
    - Iran - Spalding - Recruitment Afghanistan, 1956 November (Box 28A)
    - NEF - Finances - Miller, 1932-1958 (Box 28A)
    - 10 separate reports on various topics, 1967-1976 (Box 28A)
    - Role of Private American Assistance in Iran, George V. Allen, 1967-1968 (Box 28A)
    - C-73-15 D.O. #4 End of Tour - Smith, James E., 1976 May (Box 29)
    - C-73-15 D.O. #4 End of Tour - Van Voorthuizen, E.G., 1974 November (Box 29)
    - C-73-15 C.O. #4 (Botswana) Range Technical Results/Part 1 & 2, 1970-1975 (Box 29)
    - End of Tour AID/CM/afr C-73-15 D.O. #5, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
      - Land Development Section Staffing Patterns 1977 - 1978, 2016:FA406:004 (Folder SF4)
    - 73-15 D.O. 6, 1976 (Box 29)
    - AID/afr - C-73-15 D.O. #1 End of Tour Report - Ellithrope, Glenn L. - Lesotho, 1974-1976 (Box 29)
    - D.O. 17 - End of Tour Report - Glenn L. Ellithorpe - Conservation Engineer - Thaba Bosiu Rural Development Project, Jan. 1974- June 1977 (Box 29)
      - Untitled Blueprints, 2016:FA406:005 (Folder SF5)
    - 73-15 T.O. #1 Completion of Assignment Report - H.D. Munk, 1973-1975 (Box 29)
    - C-73-15 D.O. #4 End of Tour - Anderson, Nelson C., June 1976 (Box 29)
    - C-73-15 D.O. #4 End of Tour - McConnell, Charles B., July 1976 (Box 29)
    - D.O. 7 - Lesotho - Engineering, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
    - D.O. 19 - C1117 - Lesotho, 1976-1978 (Box 29)
    - D.O. 9 - C1117 - Eddie Daniel, 1976-1977 (Box 29)
    - D.O. 2 - C1117 - Lesotho (Box 29)
    - 73-15 D.O #1 (Box 29)
    - D.O. #7 - Cameroon, 1974 (Box 29)
    - D.O. #8 - Trip to Africa, 1974-1975 (Box 29)
    - D.O. #9 - Ethopia, 1974-1977 (Box 29)
    - D. O. #10 - Lesotho, 1974-1977 (Box 29)
    - D. O. #11 - Botswana, 1973-1978 (Box 29)
    - D. O. #12 - Botswana, 1974 (Box 29)
    - D. O. #13 - Ethopia, 1974-1977 (Box 29)
    - Albanian-American School Contract, 1930-1936 (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1950-1951 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence concerning Albanian Girl's School, 1934 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Agreement - Irwin, 1929-1930 (Box 30)
    - Albania Electricity Contract, 1927-1935 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Building - Electric, 1933-1937 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Girls School Bldg. - Repairs, 1933-1937 (Box 30)
      - New Roof for the Girls School - Albanian American Institute Blueprint, 2016:FA406:006 (Folder SF6)
    - Albania - Contracts, 1933-1938 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Customs, 1933-1937 (Box 30)
    - Dako School, 1934 (Box 30)
    - Farm Building Program - Arthur Delamarter, 1933 (Box 30)
    - Albania Files, 1938 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Finance, 1936-1937 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Finance - Banking, 1930-1936 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Finance - Farm Losses, 1932-1937 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Flood, 1937-1938 (Box 30)
    - Staffing for Schools, 1935-1936 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Government - Princesses, 1938 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Inventory, 1934-1938 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Government - Konitza Prifti, 1939-1939 (Box 30)
    - Albania - government - King Zog, 1932-1938 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Health, 1933-1935 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Herbert School, 1933 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Industries, 1937 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Integration, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Kerxhalli, Ligor, 1930-1937 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Kennedy School (Box 30)
    - Albania - Location, 1934-1936 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Personnel Proof, 1936 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Minutes, 1937 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Misc., 1931 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Mosque School, 1933-1934 (Box 30)
    - Tourist, 1934-1939 (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1938 January (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1938 February (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1938 March (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1938 July (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1938 September (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1938 October (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1939 November (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1938 December (Box 30)
    - Albania - Annual Report, 1937-1938 (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1939 (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 November - December (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 October (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 September (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 July - August (Box 30)
    - Albania - Statistics - Narratives, 1937 January - June (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 June (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 February (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 January (Box 30)
    - Albania - American Institute Boys' Farm School Yearly Report of Studies, 1934 July 1 - 1935 June 30 (Box 30)
    - Albania, 1937 March (Box 30)
    - Albania - Personnel, 1933-1940 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Personnel - Housing, 1933-1934 (Box 30)
    - Blanks and Forms, Undated (Box 30)
    - Candidates, 1935-1936 (Box 31)
    - Albania - Staffing, 1935-1936 (Box 31)
    - Albania - Political, 1933-1937 (Box 31)
    - Albania - Program, 1945 January (Box 31)
    - Albania - Program, 1933-1940 (Box 31)
    - Albania - Establ. Farm School, 1931 (Box 30)
    - Albania - Publicity, 1932-1935 (Box 31)
    - Albania - Publicity, 1932-1937 (Box 31)
    - Albania - Building - Heating, 1932-1934 (Box 31)
    - Albania - Building - Refrigeration, 1932-1937 (Box 31)